♪～
（ナルト）うお～！
久しぶりの陸地だってばよ！
It's been so long since
we've stood on dry land!
（ガイ）着いた…。
We're here!
ついに　我らは着いたのか？
新大陸に…。
Did we finally make it
to the new continent?
新大陸？
New continent?
もしかして　着いたのか？
雷の国に…。
Are you saying we've arrived
at the Land of Lightning?
（ヤマト）いや　そうじゃない。
No, we're just making
a stop at this fishing port
ここは　ただの補給に立ち寄った
漁港だよ。
to stock up on supplies.
（アオバ）まだまだ　航海は
始まったばかりだからね。
Our ocean voyage has just begun.
…ってか！？
航海を続けることが
前提であり→
So this means I have to endure
more time on the high sea
生存することが前提では～！
and try to come out of it alive?!
この港を出ると　しばらくは
どこにも寄港できない。
After we leave this port,
we won't be able to dock
for quite some time.
ふ～ん　そうなのか。
Is that so?
約２週間　この船は→
For about two weeks,
since we'll be entering
the Sea Route of Silence.
沈黙の航路に
入ることになるからな。
沈黙の航路？
The Sea Route of Silence?
あぁ　沈黙の航路とは→
Yes. The Sea Route of Silence is
an unusual area in the vast ocean.
大海原にできた
不可思議な領域でな。
そのエリアは　風も吹かず
魚も　まったくいない。
In it,
there's no wind or fish.
謎の磁場が発生し
蒸気船さえ機能しなくなる。
It is surrounded by
a mysterious magnetic field.
Even steamships can't function there.
それじゃあ
どうやって　船は進むんだ？
Then how will the boat
move forward?
運河ほどの
狭く決まった部分だけ→
There's just one strip,
as narrow as a canal,
わずかな海流が発生していて→
where a small current flows.
船は　それに乗って
進むことになる。
We'll have the boat ride
that current.
海流に乗ったら　急ぐことも
後戻りすることもできない。
Once we're on that current, we won't
be able to speed up or turn around.
ふ～ん　他人の馬の背に
のんびり乗るようなもんか。
So it will be like riding along leisurely on
the back of a horse you can't control.
まぁ　そうだ…
ただ　メリットもある。
That's true.
But there are merits to it as well.
この航路に入れば
他の船も同じ条件だ。
Every ship that enters this route
will face the same situation.
海賊や敵に襲われる心配もない。
なるほどね。
So we won't have to worry about
being attacked by pirates or an enemy.
I see.
とにかく
２週間分の食料を確保だ。
In any case, we need to stock up
on two weeks of supplies.
航路の途中で食料が尽きたら
どうしようもないから。
We can't afford to run out
while we're on this course.
食料の調達をお願いします。
So please gather food.
ナルトは　ガイ先生の分まで
頼めるかな？
Naruto, can I ask you get
Guy Sensei's share too?
お前たち　回りすぎてるぞ…。
Why are you all spinning around?
ったく　しようがねえってばよ。
Man, do I have to?
♪～
よし！　これで全部揃ったな。
Okay! That's everything.
あとは　船に戻って
出港だってばよ。
Now, I just need to get back to
the ship and we can set sail!
ちょっと　うわ！
どうした！？　どうした　おい！
What's the matter? Hey!
う…　うわ～！
大丈夫か？　悪かったってばよ。
大丈夫です。
Are you okay?
I'm sorry about that.
I'm all right.
君は　木ノ葉の忍者ですか？
ん？　おう…　まぁな。
You're a Hidden Leaf ninja,
aren't you?
Huh?
Well... yeah.
今度　五大国が連合を組んで
戦争を始めるって→
Is it true that the Five Great Nations
have formed an alliance
and are going to start a war?
ほんとですか？
そんな噂が広まってんのか？
Are those rumors going around?
うん。　ここみたいな小国は→
Yes. Small lands like ours have
no choice but to abide by their orders.
五大国の言うことに
従うしかないけど→
この漁港で
食材買っているってことは→
But seeing that you've stopped at
this fishing port and purchased provisions,
沈黙の航路を通って
雷の国にでも行くんですね。
I suppose you're going through
the Sea Route of Silence
to get to the Land of Lightning,
am I correct?
まぁ　そんなとこかな。
詳しいことは言えねえけどよ。
Yeah, that's about right.
I can't tell you much more than that.
お詫びに　おっちゃんから野菜を
買ってやりてえんだけどさ。
I wish I could buy vegetables
from you to make amends,
もう買い終わったあとだからな。
but I've already gotten
everything we need.
なら　これ　買っていきませんか？
なんだ？　これ。
Then...
How about getting one of these?
What is it?
これ　カビルダケってキノコなんです。
カビルダケ？
It's a mushroom known
as a Moldshroom.
Moldshroom?
すごくおいしいんですよ。
They're really delicious!
それに繁殖力がとても強くて
いざとなったら→
And they're very easy to propagate,
so in case of emergencies,
これを増やして食べれば→
you can grow them and eat them,
食料不足になる心配も
ありません。
and you won't have to worry
about food shortages.
沈黙の航路に行く人は→
Seafarers who set out on
the Sea Route of Silence
非常用に
必ず１つは持っていくんです。
always buy one to keep
as a last resort.
へぇ…
そんな便利なキノコがあるのか。
That's a beneficial mushroom to have!
よし！　それなら
１個買っていくぜ。
All right! I'll buy one!
じゃあ！
See you.
まいどあり！
Thank you!
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
Eat or Die! Mushrooms from Hell!
（ガイ）いやだ～！
船になんか乗らんぞ～！
I don't want to go!
I'm not getting back on board!
ここが　雲隠れの里だ！
This is the Hidden Cloud Village!
You guys are wrong!
お前たちは　間違っている！
頼みますよ　ガイさん！
Please, Guy!
You're not a spoiled brat.
駄々っ子じゃないんだから
ほんとにもう！
– You're hopeless!
– Don't wanna!
船はいやだ！
うげぇ～っ！
ガイさん！？
おい　ナルト　なんてことを…。
Guy!
Hey Naruto,
why on earth did you just...
ゲキマユ先生の
かわいくねえ駄々っ子に→
I don't have the patience
to put up with
Bushy Brow Sensei's
"cute spoiled brat" act.
つきあうことなんか
ねえってばよ。
That's for sure, but...
まぁ　それはそうだが…。
さっ　早く出港しようぜ。
Let's set sail.
ガイさん　行きますよ。
Guy, let's get going.
いきますよ　ほいっ！
– Here you go.
– Got it!
いってらっしゃ～い。
Have a safe trip!
どうやら　沈黙の航路に
入ったようだな。
It looks like we've entered
the Sea Route of Silence.
全然　周りが見えねえな。
We can't see anything around us.
And this intense humidity...
それに　すごい湿気。
あと２週間も
こんなところ進むなんて→
Just thinking about sailing through this
for two weeks makes me depressed.
なんか　気が滅入るな…。
だが　海上においては
最も安全な場所でもある。
However, this is the safest place
on the ocean.
ナルトも　この間に
ゆっくり体を休めておくんだな。
Naruto, you should use this time to rest.
わかったってばよ。
I know.
どうしたんだよ　ヤマト隊長！
What's the matter, Captain Yamato?
いや…　なんでもない。
No, it's nothing.
ヤマト！　ヤマト　しっかりしろ！
Yamato!
Yamato! Get a hold of yourself!
突然　苦しみ出して
倒れちまったんだよ。
He suddenly collapsed in pain.
今のところ
休んでいてもらうしか…。
All we can do at this point
is have him rest.
Did something happen?
何かあったのか？
ゲキマユ先生！
Bushy Brow Sensei!
船酔いは　大丈夫なのか？
What happened to
your seasickness?
あぁ。　沈黙の航路に入ったら
船の揺れがおさまったんで→
The swaying subsided once
we entered the Sea Route of Silence,
and so did my seasickness.
俺の船酔いも
治っちまったってわけだ。
I see.
そっか　先生が治ったと思ったら
今度は　ヤマト隊長か…。
Just when you start feeling better,
it's Captain Yamato's turn.
えっ？　ヤマトに何かあったのか？
What happened to Yamato?
詳しくはわかりません。
We don't know for certain.
It seems something is
eroding Yamato's chakra.
ですが
どうやら　ヤマトさんのチャクラが→
何かに
侵食されているようですね。
ヤマトのチャクラが？
Yamato's chakra?
原因不明の症状です。
We still don't know
what's causing his symptoms.
原因不明って…。
So does that mean...
大変です！
どうした？
Bad news!
What is it?!
それが…　とにかく来てください。
Please come with me!
何だ！？　これは。
キノコ？
What are these?!
Mushrooms?!
Did some spores get mixed in
with our provisions?
食料に菌が紛れ込んだ
というのか。
俺がカビルダケってキノコを
買っておいたけど→
I bought a mushroom
called a Moldshroom.
たった１個だし→
But only one.
こんな毒々しい色の
キノコじゃなかったってばよ。
And it didn't have
a poisonous-looking color like these.
船にある食料は
ここにあるのがすべてです。
The ship's entire food supply
is right here.
それじゃ　食料は全滅？
Does that mean all of
our food supply is destroyed?
Does this mean the only thing
we can eat are these mushrooms?
ということは　食べられるものは
このキノコだけか。
Check out their coloring.
けど　この色
どう見たって毒キノコだろ。
They look like
poisonous mushrooms to me.
食料だけじゃない。
水も全滅している。
It's not just the food.
Our water is gone too.
そんな　食い物も水もねえんじゃ
話になんねえってばよ。
No way! We can't go on
without food or water.
We have to turn
this ship around...
急いで船を戻…。
いいや　無理だ。
We can't. Once we're on
the Sea Route of Silence,
一度
沈黙の航路に入ったからには→
turning back is impossible.
後戻りは不可能だ。
But we just got on the route!
だって　航路に入ったばっかだぞ。
So we have two weeks until
we can get off of this course?
抜けるまでには
あと２週間はかかるんだろ。
その間　我々は
飲まず食わずで→
It means we are just
going to have to endure
航海を続けなければならない
というわけだ。
without eating or drinking!
マジかよ…。
Are you kidding me?!
《そうは言ったって
どっかに魚の１匹くらい…》
Still...
There's gotta be at least one fish.
《鳥の１羽くらい…》
Or at least one bird.
《何もいねえ…》
There's nothing!
以前　熱き青春の真っただ中→
Once before, during the peak
of my passionate days of youth,
I trained by fasting.
断食の修業をしたことがある。
人間が１日に消費するのは
１，６００キロカロリー。
A human burns
1600 calories each day.
栄養摂取が行われずにいると→
Without nutrients,
the human body converts
人間は　自分の筋肉を
タンパク質に変え→
its own muscle into protein
and turns fat into energy.
脂肪をエネルギーに変えていく。
これが続くかぎり
餓死したりしない。
As long as this continues,
you will not starve to death.
Starve to death... I hope not.
餓死しないって
そうは思えねえってばよ。
But that's as long as
you stay sufficiently hydrated.
それは　水分補給が
十分　行われている状態で→
今は　そのかぎりではない。
Right now, we're in
the opposite situation.
At this rate,
このままでは
いかに情熱がたぎる大人でも→
even the most determined adult
will die in one to two weeks.
１週間から２週間で死亡する。
今　いったい何日目だ？
What day is this?!
I don't know.
A week might have passed already.
わからん…
１週間は経っているかもしれん。
腹が減りすぎて　俺の腹時計も
とっくに止まっちまってる。
I've been hungry so long,
my stomach can't tell the time anymore.
このままなら　我々は
間違いなく餓死する。
If this goes on, we're definitely
going to starve to death.
最後の賭けに
出るべきかもしれんな。
Perhaps it's time for our last gamble.
最後の賭け？
Our last gamble?
ついてこい　ナルト。
Follow me, Naruto.
まさか　最後の賭けって…。
No way. This is your last gamble?
Yes, this is it!
そのまさかだ
こいつが食べられれば。
If these are edible...
They sure look poisonous to me.
けど　どう見たって毒キノコだぞ。
But these mushrooms could
be absolutely delicious.
だが　このキノコは　とんでもなく
おいしいかもしれん。
とにかく　我々は何かを
食べなければ餓死する。
And if we don't eat anything,
we will die.
そらそうだけど。
I know, but...
Naruto, let's do
rock-paper-scissors right now.
ナルト　ここは　ジャンケンだ。
よし　俺は覚悟を決めた。
All right! I'm ready for this!
いくぞ　ナルト。
Here we go, Naruto!
（２人）最初は　グー！　ジャンケン　ポン！
- Ready, set, go!
- Rock-paper-scissors!
All right! I win!
よっしゃ～　勝った　勝った。
俺の勝ちだ。
I win!
グォ～
やはり　ナルトは　パーだったか。
I should've known
you'd go with paper!
パーって　なんか　トゲを感じる
言い方だってばよ。
That doesn't sound too flattering.
グゥ～。
Sensei, now's the time to be a man
and step up.
先生
ここは男らしく腹をくくって。
ククッ　フフッ…。
ゲキマユ先生？
ハッハッハッハッ！
Bushy Brow Sensei?
W-What's going on?
Have you lost it?
どうなっちまったんだ？
ついに壊れちまったのか？
いいや　ナルト
私はこの事態を喜んでいる。
No, Naruto.
I'm relishing this moment.
えっ？
Huh?
I've been waiting for this moment!
むしろ　私は
この瞬間を待っていた。
いただきま～す！
Thank you for the food!
ゲキマユ先生…　大丈夫か？
Bushy Brow Sensei,
are you okay?
So the mushrooms were
poisonous, after all!
やっぱり　毒キノコか！？
ウホホ…　こりゃ　うまい。
These are delicious.
I've never eaten anything so good!
今まで　こんなうまいもの
食ったことはない。
どうして　こんなものを
食べずにいたんだ。
How could I not have
eaten them until now?!
ゲキマユ先生　それがうまいって
ほんとなのか？
Bushy Brow Sensei,
are you sure they taste good?
食うぞ　食うぞ
俺が全部食ってやる！
I'm going to eat them!
I'll eat them all up!
Wait! Hey wait!
Me too! I'm gonna eat too!
待て　待てってばよ！
俺も　俺も食う！
ほんとだ　こりゃうまいってばよ。
止まらないってばよ。
Hey, you're right!
They taste great! I can't stop!
グフフ…　なんか
すっげえ気分がよくなってきた。
I'm starting to feel really good!
グフフ…　俺もだ。
Me too.
体の底から活力が湧いてくる。
グハハハハ！
I feel energy rising from
deep inside my body.
グフフ…　そこにまだ
キノコが残ってたってばよ。
There are some more
mushrooms over there.
ガルルルル！
このキノコは　すべて私のものだ。
Those mushrooms are all mine!
くらえ　キノコ旋風！
Take this!
Mushroom Hurricane!
そりゃ～！
I know what your weakness is,
Bushy Brow Sensei!
ゲキマユ先生の弱点なんて
わかってるぜ。
Ninja Art! Mushroom Harem Jutsu!
忍法　キノコハーレムの術！
うっふ～ん。
Bushy Brow Sensei...
ゲキマユ先生！
So handsome!
す　て　き！
遊びましょう。
Let's have some fun!
So naïve!
あま～い！　そんなもので
私の熱血鼻血は発射せんぞ。
You think something like that will
make me get a nosebleed?!
キノコ大旋風！
Great Mushroom Hurricane!
むっ！？
もらった！　キノコ螺旋丸！
You're mine!
Mushroom Rasengan!
Too easy, Naruto!
あまいぞ　ナルト！
Not bad!
Shadow Clones, huh?
やるな　影分身か。
The real one's over here!
本物は　こっちだってばよ
キノコ螺旋丸！
Mushroom Rasengan!
ぬおっ！？　キノコ強力旋風！
Severe Mushroom Hurricane!
うおぉ～！
ぐわっ…。
とりゃ～！　ぐえっ…。
おえ～。
うぅ…
なんで　こんなことになったんだ。
How did this happen?
I should have never
bought that mushroom.
《あんなキノコさえ
買わなければ…》
Damn it!
クソッ　何でもいい
口に食い物を…　口に…。
Who cares now.
I need to put food in my mouth.
In my mouth.
あっ　その手があったか。
That's it!
Ninja Art:
Mushroom Summoning Jutsu!
忍法　キノコ口寄せの術！
Hey Naruto, what do you want?
（ガマ竜）あれ～　ナルト　何の用なの？
What's this?
あれ～
メチャうまそうじゃねえかよ。
You look so yummy!
I'm gonna eat you!
食ってやる！
うわぁ～！
どうやら
全員くたばったようだな。
It looks like they're all dead.
They intended to go to
the Land of Lightning.
こいつらは
雷の国に行くつもりだった。
They must have some kind
of treasure on board.
おそらく
何か　お宝を積んでるはずだぜ。
I admire your cleverness, Boss!
まったく　お頭の頭のよさには
感心しますぜ。
ハハッ　たったキノコ１本で
海賊してるんですからね。
Yeah, he's a pirate that operates
with a single mushroom.
The Moldshroom is just
an ordinary mushroom.
カビルダケってのは
普通は　ただのキノコだが→
But if you keep it in a dark,
humid place for more than a day,
１日以上　暗闇と湿気に置くと→
it turns into a very toxic mushroom
that propagates rapidly.
強力な毒キノコに変わって
異常繁殖するのさ。
It wreaks havoc on
the Sea Route of Silence.
沈黙の航路じゃ
とんでもねえ猛威をふるう。
And they probably had
no clue what hit them.
そうとも知らねえで。
All right, guys!
Go and find the treasure!
さぁ　おめえたち　お宝を探すぜ！
– Right!
（２人）ヘイ！
So it was all your doing.
やっぱり
てめえの仕業だったんだな。
なっ…　なんで　おめえたち！？
Hey, how come you guys are...
You guys were supposed
to have starved to death!
てめえら
餓死したはずじゃねえのか！？
I almost gave in.
見るものが　なんでも
食い物に見えちまうぐらい→
I was so hungry that I was about
to eat everything in sight.
腹減ってたからな。
危なく　そうなっちまう
ところだったけどよ。
どわ～！　待て　待て　ガマ竜！
Wait, wait, wait, Gamatatsu!
だって
おいしいから食べていいって…。
Eat up! Naruto, it tastes good. Eat.
Stupid!
バカ！　俺が　お前を食べるはずで
お前なんか…。
I'm gonna eat you and you're...
I know! I have a good idea!
そうだ！
いい考えがあったってばよ！
((この際
なんでも我慢するってばよ！))
At this point, I'll endure anything.
I asked Gamatatsu to bring back
some of Granny Shima's cooking!
ガマ竜に頼んで
シマばあちゃんの料理を→
運んでもらったんだってばよ。
クーッ　そんな手が…。
So you had a trick up your sleeve?!
Thanks to her, we ate enough
bug cuisine to last a lifetime.
おかげで　我々は→
虫料理を死ぬほど
食うことになってしまった。
Just thinking about how that tasted...
あの味を思い出すと…。
We're gonna give it back to you...
この　お礼は
たんまり　させてもらうぜ！
real good!
うわぁ～！
おっ　普通の波に戻ったぞ！
The waves are back to normal!
But look at this mess.
しかし　この荒れようは
いったい何があったというのだ。
What happened here?
Do you know Naruto?
ナルト　知らないか？
あ？
My memory's been fuzzy
ever since I ate those mushrooms.
そういえば
キノコを食ってからの記憶が→
あいまいだってばよ。
But, this is a real mess.
それにしても
ひでえ荒れようだな。
It looks like pirates raided us.
まるで
海賊にでも襲われたみてえだ。
Yeah, this is awful.
Yamato's going to be very upset.
あぁ　メチャクチャだ　ヤマトが怒るな。
知らない間に→
Maybe something awful happened
before we realized it.
何か　すげえことが
あったのかもしれねえってばよ。
うぅ…　急に船酔いが！
I suddenly feel seasick.
またかよ…　ゲキマユ先生。
Not again, Bushy Brow Sensei.
♪～
気がついたか？　ヤマト。
Are you awake, Yamato?!
What happened to me?
私は　どうしたんですか？
You became host to
a kind of parasitic fungus
キノコの菌糸が　お前に寄生をして→
that sucked out
your Wood Style Chakra.
木遁のチャクラを
吸い上げていたようだ。
でも　もう大丈夫だ。
You'll be all right now.
I can't believe there's a mushroom
that can cause so much suffering.
まさか　俺たちをこんなに苦しめる
キノコがあるなんてな。
Just goes to show you
how vast this world is.
まだ世界は広い
ってことだってばよ。
What are you going to do with us?
俺たちをどうするつもりだ！？
Apparently, the Sea Route of Silence
has a way back.
沈黙の航路には
戻るルートもあるそうだな。
You're not planning to send us there?
まさか　そこに俺たちを！？
そのまさかだ。
Exactly.
The route takes two weeks to clear!
あの航路は
２週間もあるんだぞ！？
What about food during that time?!
その間の食料は！？
You don't have to worry about that.
それは　心配ねえってばよ。
ん？　これは…。
This is...
You guys can fill your bellies
with that mushroom!
お前たちも　腹いっぱい
このキノコを味わうといいってばよ。
See ya!
じゃあな。
Wood Style!
木遁！
H-Hey wait!
おい！　おい！
ちょっ…　うわ～！
S-Stop! Please stop this!
やめろ！
やめてくれよ～　おい！
Help us!
助けてくれ～！
A mushroom hot pot?!
キノコ鍋って…。
It can't be helped.
All of our provisions are gone.
しようがないだろう
食料が　全滅しているんだ。
Until we reach the nearest port,
all we have are...
近くの港に寄るまで　あるのは→
Mushrooms or bugs!
キノコか　虫だ！
ぐわっ！　もうどっちも
勘弁だってばよ～。
C'mon... Give me a break from
both of those things!
ん？　このキノコ
意外とうまいじゃないか。
– These mushrooms are quite good!
– Naruto, this one is better, try it.
おい　ナルト　食ってみろ。
– Hurry and just eat!
– No way!
もっと　まともなもんが
食いてえ！
I just want something normal to eat!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokyuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
dance dance dance to you
just just just to you
akai itode tsunagacchattenda
We're connected by the Red String of Fate
dareka ga dareka wo damashite achichi
Somebody is doing something
burning hot by deceiving somebody
sonna de iinoka?
Are you OK with that?
ore wa chigauze baka ni sunjanee
I'm not like them. You don't know the first thing about me
kitanai kirei giragira no sora
The dirty, beautiful sky glitters
antanimo mieterunokai?
Can you see it too?
hageshiku aishi aisareta koto wa arunokai?
Have you ever loved, and been loved, passionately?
ore to anta no kizuna wa dounatterundai?
What's become of our bond?
c'mon!
haato dokyun de bachibachi sunzen
My heart is thumping and about to explode
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! doki dokuun!!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!!! Thump-thump-bang!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie! aini mudawanee!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Love is it!
ieieie! ieieie! ieieie!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Next Episode
What are they doing?
＜　まずは…＞
Seems like Naruto and his clones are fighting.
That's good!
Men fighting, colliding as their hot blood circulates!
I like this!
Doesn't seem like that's the case here.
We're taking control of this ship.
If you value the life of the real Naruto,
＜　そうなんです！
日本人が今はじめてみたい事…＞
you will unconditionally fulfill all of our demands!
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Revenge of the Shadow Clones"
Revenge of the Shadow Clones
＜　ご存じかしら？
日本のランニング人口は→
It's one hassle after another.
近年　劇的に上昇！＞